#### **Ben Anderson**

design.benanderson@gmail.com · (720) 297-6474 Portfolio Site LinkedIn Profile

Hello! My name is Ben and I've been designing web and mobile experiences for over six years. Since 2021 I've also built design systems and UI libraries for a team of 18+ designers. You'll find me in Figma obsessing over components, libraries, autolayout behavior, animations and prototypes.

Experience

### JumpCloud

Senior Product Designer, Platform Experience (August 2021 – Present)

**Stratus Web Design System** serves all of JumpCloud's web platforms and 18+ UX designers. I created a Figma library containing 80+ UI components, a dozen full page templates and hundreds (if not thousands) of variants. Each Figma component mirrors a Vue code component used by our front end developers.

**JumpCloud MTP** allows IT administrators to serve multiple client organizations from a single pane of glass. I've led UX for this product since 2021, focusing on new features like integrations, license usage and payment history. I also developed new UI components and patterns for navigation, list and detail views, status cards, bulk actions, and quick actions for application across all other JumpCloud platforms.

**Password Manager** lets JumpCloud end users securely store and share passwords. I supported this project by designing key flows for onboarding, user enrollment, shared folder management, and usage insights. It also provided a great opportunity to apply design system patterns and new UI components.

**Asset Directory** helps IT admins to provision, track and manage all of the hardware and software assets used by employees across their org. I supported this project by designing list and detail views, asset creation flows, user assignment flows, and usage insights.

## PGi

Senior Product Designer (July 2019 – April 2021) Product Designer (March 2018 – June 2019)

**GlobalMeet Webcast** is a live video streaming platform for enterprise companies. I led a vision-oriented redesign for this web app by creating all new UI, navigation and page structures, as well as flows for event creation, event delivery, recording, chat and analytics. I also turned all that into a high-fidelity prototype for user testing and a promotional video.

**GlobalMeet Mobile** is a platform for web conferencing and unified business communications. I led UX for these iOS and Android apps from 2018 to 2020, focusing

on UI updates and new features like smart notifications, messaging, calling and video conferencing.

## ReadyTalk

User Experience Designer (January 2017 – February 2018) Visual Designer (December 2015 – December 2016)

**Illuminate Webcast** is a live and simulated live video streaming platform purpose-built for marketers. I led UX for this new web app by creating branding, UI, navigation and page structures as well as flows for event creation, event delivery, recording, chat and white label customization.

**ReadyTalk.com** provides marketing and support information for their conferencing and webcast products. I redesigned the site to it make it easier for potential customers to find the right solutions, understanding pricing, dive into technical specs and self-serve or connect with sales. It was also a great opportunity to update the visual identity while building on existing brand recognition.

**Foxden Video Conferencing** allows users to virtually meet and share content without downloads or plugins. I designed the visual identity, website, marketing collateral, and promotional videos.

## Nuby

Industrial Designer (July 2013 – November 2015)

**Nuby** makes toys, teethers and feeding products for babies and toddlers. I designed new products from sketch to refined drawings, to 3D models, renders and prototypes, to materials and finishes, and finally to manufactured pieces for worldwide distribution.

# Education

# **University of Bradford**

MBA - Innovation, Enterprise & Circular Economy (2015 – 2018)

# Savannah College of Art & Design

BFA - Industrial Design (2007 – 2011)

Tools

## **Figma**

Components, variants, styles, libraries, autolayout, prototyping

## **Additional UX**

Sketch, XD, ProtoPie, Usertesting.com

#### Web

HTML, CSS, Webflow

## Adobe

Photoshop, Illustrator, AfterEffects

View my work at <u>andersonxd.com</u>